shippit.com 2017-06-06

# Shippit

### Shippits' Privacy Policy

It is Shippit's intention to make every effort possible to safeguard the integrity of your personal details and correspondence. Shippit have implemented a comprehensive "Privacy Policy" in order to facilitate its ability to protect the integrity of the information that it possesses. However, certain circumstances may arise where Shippit cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personally identifiable information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. By way of example (without limiting the foregoing), Shippit may be legally forced to disclose information to the government or third parties under certain circumstances, or third parties may unlawfully and without its knowledge intercept or access transmissions or private communications. Shippit can (and you authorise it to) disclose any information about you to law enforcement or other governmental officials as Shippit, in its sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate, in connection any legal requirement to do with an investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringements, piracy or any other activity that is illegal or may expose Shippit and/or its offices to legal liability.

Therefore, although Shippit shall endeavour to take every reasonable step possible in accordance with the Privacy Act and industry standards to protect your privacy, Shippit do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personally identifiable information or private communications will remain private.

#### Procedures

As part of Shippit's normal operation to provide you with a courier service, Shippit needs to collect some information about you. Specifically, your name & address (Both billing and pick-up address) and other criteria specific to your special conditions required of Shippit to provide you with a service that meets your expectations. This information is used only to enable Shippit to service your courier needs and subsequent financial transactions (eg. invoicing). Shippit does not sell, rent or distribute your information to any third party or contractor, or use this information for any other reason than as a means for Shippit to identify you for the purposes of providing an efficient courier service and invoicing.

You should be aware that Shippit shall give your Pick-up address details and other pertinent information to its sub-contracted couriers. However, Shippit only furnishes its sub-contracted couriers with sufficient information to do the job and all historical or other information that it has collected about you is for Shippit's use only and is not given to its sub-contracted couriers.

Shippit may use your email address, your mailing address, and phone number(s) to contact you regarding administrative notices, new product offerings, and communications relevant to your use of Shippit Courier's products and services. If you do not wish to receive these communications, you have the ability to request, either by fax, email or letter, that Shippit cease communicating with your organisation on all matters unrelated to accounting matters. (Refer below for address details and procedures for Access)

In addition to your address details, Shippit maintains a history of your courier job details and relevant commentary from yourself, Shippit's couriers or its operation's staff pertaining to any aspect, both good or bad, that have a bearing on a particular courier job or Shippit's service in general. Shippit use this information and other information it obtains from your current and past activities at Shippit, to resolve disputes, trouble-shoot problems and enforce Shippit's commitment to provide a consistent courier service to you and your organisation.

#### Internet & Cookies

If you choose to use Shippit's Internet booking facility, you should be aware that Shippit uses cookies. These cookies are innocuous in that they are only transient or session cookies. In other words they are automatically deleted when you terminate the booking session with Shippit or close your browser. The only thing that is stored in this cookie is your Login ID and password. The reason why Shippit uses cookies is that cookies allow you to only have to enter your Login ID & password once during a session. This is unfortunately necessary to guarantee your privacy throughout the Internet booking procedure. However, if you do not wish to use cookies, then it is suggested that you use the telephone booking facility on 136331 instead, as there is no provision to provide a viable Internet Booking facility that does not incorporate cookies. Furthermore, Shippit does not use your cookie to track your activity or record any information about you.

#### Data Security

To further protect you while utilising Shippit's Internet Booking facility, it, has implemented an encryption mechanism (SSL - Secure Socket Layer) so that all information on its Web site and Internet Bookings facility is automatically encrypted, providing a level of security to its clients. 

We use eWay or PayPal to process your credit card infomation. This data is not seen or stored by our systems.

Your Information is stored on Shippit's server located at its premise at Mosman. Shippit uses industry standards in its efforts to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal identifiable information, such as firewalls and Secure Socket Layers. However, "perfect security" does not exist on the Internet. Additionally, Shippit removes copies of your information "off site" as part of its "Tape Backup Procedure". These tapes are held in a secure location overnight, in the custody of senior management and are returned to Shippit during the day.

If you send Shippit personal correspondence, such as emails or letters, or if other users or third parties send it correspondence about your activities, Shippit may collect such information into a file specific to you.

#### Access

To ensure that all requests relating to the Privacy Act, are handled expeditiously and with the upmost confidentiality, Shippit will only accept requests in writing. Therefore, should you wish to examine your information and or make corrections to it or register a complaint relating to the Privacy Policy, then you must present this request in writing to Shippit. You should address it to:

 **The Privacy Manager**  
Shippit Pty Ltd  
Suite 44, Jones Bay Wharf, 26-32 Pirrama Rd, Pyrmont, NSW 2009  
-

or alternatively via email at: [info@shippit.com](mailto:info@shippit.com)

In accordance with the Privacy Act, upon written request, Shippit will provide you with access to your relevant information, via a computer terminal on the premises of Shippit's office at Mosman. You will be provided with adequate privacy and convenience of access, to enable you to peruse your information. You will not be charged for this facility.

However, if you require a different means to access this information or that it be presented in a different format to the way that it is stored or displayed, then Shippit will charge you for any materials or time that is necessary to compile your information in the format that you have requested.

If you believe that the information that Shippit has about you is incorrect, then you may submit a written request that it be rectified. If Shippit agree with your request, then this information will be updated accordingly. However, if Shippit dispute your claim that the information it has relating to you is incorrect, then at your request, Shippit will take reasonable steps to associate with the information of your claim to this effect. (ie Shippit will put a mark or a note on the information to indicate that the statement exists and where it can be found.) Furthermore, Shippit will tell you in writing the reasons for refusing to correct your personal information.

Under certain circumstances, Shippit may refuse your request to access your information for such reason as but not limited to; access to personal information about them if giving access would be unlawful, if required or authorised by law, if it would prejudice an investigation, if it would prejudice activities of enforcement bodies or cause damage to security of Australia In this situation Shippit will tell you in writing any reasons it has for denying access to information.

These reasons will be presented to you in writing, explaining the reasons for denying access or refusing to attach a correction statement. Included in this letter will be the details covering any process Shippit had for reviewing the decision and the process you may follow if you wish to make a complaint about the decision, either to the federal Privacy Commissioner or the relevant code adjudicator.
